Welcome to the family.
The Fantastic 4: First Steps is a science fiction,
adventure, action film directed by Matt Shakman.
Against the vibrant backdrop of a 1960s-inspired, retro-futuristic world, Marvel's First Family is forced to balance their roles as heroes with the
strength of their family bond, while defending Earth from a ravenous space god called Galactus and his enigmatic Herald, Silver Surfer.
Reed Richards / Mister Fantastic, played by Pedro Pascal.
Sue Storm / Invisible Woman, played by Vanessa Kirby.
Ben Grimm / The Thing, played by Ebon Moss-Bachrach.
Johnny Storm / Human Torch, played by Joseph Quinn.
Galactus, played by Ralph Ineson.
Shalla-Bal / Silver Surfer, played by Julia Garner.
The Fantastic Four: First Steps is a 2025 American superhero film based
on the Marvel Comics superhero team the Fantastic Four.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is the 37th film in
the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU) and the second reboot of the Fantastic Four film series.
The film was directed by Matt Shakman from a screenplay by Josh Friedman,
Eric Pearson, and the team of Jeff Kaplan and Ian Springer.
It features an ensemble cast including Pedro Pascal, Vanessa Kirby, Ebon Moss-Bachrach, and Joseph Quinn as the titular
team, alongside Julia Garner, Sarah Niles, Mark Gatiss, Natasha Lyonne, Paul Walter Hauser, and Ralph Ineson.
The film is set in the 1960s of a retro-futuristic world which the Fantastic Four
must protect from the planet-devouring cosmic being Galactus (Ineson).
20th Century Fox began work on a new Fantastic Four film
following the failure of Fantastic Four (2015).
After the studio was acquired by Disney in March 2019, control of the franchise was
transferred to Marvel Studios, and a new film was announced that July.
Jon Watts was set to direct in December 2020, but stepped down in April 2022.
Shakman replaced him that September when Kaplan and
Springer were working on the script.
Casting began by early 2023, and Friedman joined in March to rewrite the script.
The film is differentiated from previous Fantastic Four
films by avoiding the team's origin story.
Pearson joined to polish the script by mid-February 2024, when the main
cast and the title The Fantastic Four were announced.
The subtitle was added in July, when filming began.
It took place until November 2024 at Pinewood Studios in
England, and on location in England and Spain.
The Fantastic Four: First Steps premiered at the Dorothy Chandler Pavilion in Los Angeles on July 21, 2025,
and was released in the United States on July 25, as the first film in Phase Six of the MCU.
It received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed $521.9 million
worldwide, making it the highest-grossing Fantastic Four film.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of strong woman, superhero,
based on comic, end of the world, family.
The tone is thought_provoking.